

Yanick Senn

E-Mail info@yanicksenn.com
Website yanicksenn.com

GitHub github.com/yanicksenn

Highlights Java, Kotlin, C#, SQL, Maven, Docker, Spring,

Typescript, Angular, JavaScript, HTML/CSS

Summary

Skilled software engineer with 6+ years of working experience and a BSc in Computer Science. A quick learner who can absorb and contribute new ideas and concepts. Always pushing to reduce technical debt and optimizing processes in software development. Experienced in OOP and functional programming as well as TDD, BDD, and property-based testing. Reliable team player with strong oral and written communication skills. Staying in the loop through contributions to open-source and personal projects.

Education

ZHAW School of EngineeringBSc in Computer Science
2018 – 2022

BBB Berufsbildung Baden Baden

Federal VET Diploma (Application developer EFZ) 2012 – 2016 Vocational baccalaureate (BMS) 2012 – 2016

Experience

Worldline Schweiz AG Zürich

Software-Engineer

Feb. 2021 - Now

- Developed and maintained software to handle the processing of card payments.
- Held technical interviews with potential new employees.
- Took ownership in various projects regarding PCI DSS.
- Presented newly developed components and tools in department wide trainings.

Java Kotlin PL/SQL Spring Eclipse-RCP Docker Maven Shell

aXenta AG 2016 – Jan. 2021

Software-Engineer (Full Stack)

- Designed, developed, and maintained a web-interface called PKCockpit for second-pillar pension funds.
- · Developed specific rest services for clients using PKCockpit.
- Held department wide trainings for unit, integration, and property-based testing.
- Organized a company internal hackathon to evaluate a suitable web-framework for PKCockpit.

Java | Java EE | TypeScript | Angular | HTML/CSS | PL/SQL | AWT/Swing | Gradle

aXenta AG 2012 – 2016

Software-Engineer Apprentice

- Resolved software bugs and participated in company internal projects.
- Implemented an iOS application that allows full-text search for Swiss laws.
- Developed a tool to unify and automate screenshots for release manuals of new features. (IPA)

Java | PL/SQL | EJB2 / EJB3 | AWT/Swing | Objective-C | Batch

Languages

Java Kotlin C#

SQL / PL/SQL

Shell / Bash / Batch / PowerShell

TypeScript / JavaScript

HTML / CSS

Other

Agile / SCRUM TDD / BDD OOP / Functional Programming Blockchain Development with Solidity Microsoft Office

About myself

Non programming languages

- German (Mother tongue)
- English

Interests

- Motorsports (Go-Kart in Swiss National Championship)
- Game-Development
- Gaming
- Drums

Frameworks & Tools

Maven / Gradle Spring / Spring-Boot Docker / Podman Unity3d Node.js / Angular Jenkins Git / Perforce